Charles Tucker Barrett

ctbarrett.tech@gmail.com | 919-999-7792 | Charlotte, NC

Website: https://tucker.tech

GitHub: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett | **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tucker-barrett

Summary

Full stack developer with a previous career in music education. Experienced working on collaborative teams, spontaneous problem-solving, and devising creative approaches to difficult situations. Possess a Full Stack Web Development certificate and have a genuine love for technology and the arts.

Technical Skills

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, React, React Native, Expo, Express, Node.js, SQL (MySQL, Sequelize), NoSQL (MongoDB, Mongoose), API (RESTful, GraphQL), Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Testing (Jest), Deployment (Heroku, Netlify), CSS Libraries (Bootstrap, Bulma), Insomnia/Postman, Git/GitHub, Scrum/Agile, Jira, Figma, HTML/CSS

Salesforce: Apex, LWC, OmniStudio

Experience

Associate Technical Consultant - Salesforce - (May 2022 - present)

- ♦ Deliver customized solutions to clients using the Salesforce platform at all levels of the stack, including technologies like Apex, Lightning Web Components, and OmniStudio.
- ♦ Leverage OmniStudio components such OmniScripts, Integration Procedures, and DataRaptors alongside custom Apex classes and Lightning Web Components to create a robust application that empowers large manufacturing companies to apply for grant funding.
- Confer with project stakeholders to help determine the most appropriate application design choices.

Senior Tutor / Teaching Assistant - 2U - (January 2022 - present)

- Guide students in their learning of web development technologies in small group and individual formats.
- Instruct students on development best practices and strategies in a project-based curriculum with a focus on JavaScript, Node.js, React, SQL, MongoDB, and RESTful and GraphQL APIs.
- Assist students with planning, designing, and getting started on their web applications, as well as debugging and improving existing code.
- Empower students to be confident, skilled debuggers, and to be more self-guided post-bootcamp.

Specialist - *Apple* - (2021 - 2022)

- ♦ Utilized thorough product knowledge to provide personalized solutions for new Apple product owners.
- Employed methodical troubleshooting techniques to solve technical issues for customers.
- Educated customers on how to get the most out of their products.

ESL Teacher - *VIPKid* - (2018 - 2022)

- ♦ Executed engaging virtual lessons to capture and retain the attention of students aged 4-16.
- ♦ Maintained a nearly 100% rebooking rate 100% 5/5 star-rated teacher.
- ♦ Managed relationships with students and parents, grew strong rapport.

Music Teacher - South Harnett Elementary School, Bunnlevel, NC - (2019 - 2021)

- ♦ Developed and implemented a comprehensive music curriculum for grades 1-5 and K-5 special needs.
- Planned and executed successful performances, ensuring students' personal and musical growth.
- ♦ Adjusted my curriculum to be accessible from anywhere after the outbreak of COVID-19.

Kindergarten/ESL Teacher - Worwick Franklin Institute, Ulsan, South Korea - (2015 - 2018)

- As a founding teacher of the academy, established a complete kindergarten curriculum with a focus on ESL education in an English immersion environment.
- Contributed to a nearly 200% increase in enrollment after my first year.
- Bridged language and cultural divides to collaborate with Korean coworkers.

Projects

Ridoughculous | In Progress

- ♦ Calculator allowing users to determine proportions for dough recipes | React Native, Expo, TypeScript
- Utilizes React Native for a modular component structure with TypeScript to ensure type safety.
- Uses Expo for development, building, and deployment.
- ◆ Repository: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/ridoughculous

CoinBull | https://coinbull.herokuapp.com/

- ♦ Full stack web application to track cryptocurrency information | MERN stack, GraphQL, Heroku
- Utilized React to build a modular front end architecture to ensure maximum efficiency and update the DOM with data from multiple external cryptocurrency APIs.
- ♦ Implemented a GraphQL API alongside a MongoDB/Mongoose back end to store and query user data.
- ◆ Repository: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/CoinBull

Book Search Engine | https://ctb-book-search.herokuapp.com/

- Full stack web application to search for and save books | MERN stack, GraphQL, Heroku
- Refactored an existing REST API to instead use GraphQL to query and mutate data.
- ♦ Repository: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/book-search-engine

Skillet & Shaker | https://grinninbarrett.github.io/recipe-finder

- ♦ Uses recipe APIs to find food and drink recipes based on user criteria | JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- ♦ Leveraged "vanilla" JavaScript, HTML, and the Bulma CSS library to create a fast, seamless user experience.
- Utilizes local storage to allow users to save their favorite recipes for future reference.
- Repository: https://github.com/grinninbarrett/recipe-finder

Etch-a-Sketch | https://grinninbarrett.github.io/etch-a-sketch

- ♦ Drawing canvas based on the famous Etch-a-Sketch | JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- ♦ Manipulates the DOM using JavaScript, allowing users to customize various aspects of the drawing canvas, such as color and pixel density.
- ♦ Employs CSS Flexbox to create a responsive layout so as to be usable on any device.
- ♦ Repository: https://github.com/grinninbarrett/etch-a-sketch

Wasted Class Time | https://grinninbarrett.github.io/wasted-class-time/

- ◆ Timer to calculate percentage of class wasted by poor student behavior | JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- ♦ Leveraged JavaScript to perform calculations based on the timer and user-entered class time.
- ◆ Repository: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/wasted-class-time

Leadership / Honors

- ♦ President, Phi Mu Alpha Sinfonia, Delta Sigma Chapter, Columbia, SC 2010 2011
- ♦ Drum Major, USC Marching Band, Columbia, SC 2009 2010
- ♦ Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America, Troop 222, Abingdon, VA

Certificates / Certifications

- ♦ Certified Administrator, Salesforce
- ◆ Certified Platform App Builder, Salesforce
- ◆ Certified OmniStudio Developer, **Salesforce**
- ◆ Certified OmniStudio Consultant, Salesforce
- ♦ Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, MITx
- ♦ Responsive Web Design, freeCodeCamp

Education

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC - 2021

Certificate - JavaScript Full Stack Web Development

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC - 2012

Bachelor of Music Education with Horn Performance Certificate